<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vmware on Beautiful Hugo</title>
    <link>/categories/vmware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vmware on Beautiful Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 22:49:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alerting on &#34;Bootbank cannot be found at path ‘/bootbank’&#34; in vRealize Operations</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/bootbank-cannot-be-found-at-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 22:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/bootbank-cannot-be-found-at-path/</guid>
      <description>If you boot your ESXi hosts from SD-cards or USB you might have run into this issue. Suddenly your host(s) displays the following under events: &amp;ldquo;Bootbank cannot be found at path ‘/bootbank’.&amp;rdquo;
Usually this means that the boot device has been corrupted somehow, either due to a device failure or other issues. Normally the host continues to run, until it&amp;rsquo;s rebooted that is&amp;hellip;
For some reason, vRealize Operations doesn&amp;rsquo;t pick this up as a host issue that it alerts on, so if your alerting regime is based on vROps alerts, you might not get alerted immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross vCenter VM Mobility Fling - macOS?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/cross-vcenter-vm-mobility-fling-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 11:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/cross-vcenter-vm-mobility-fling-macos/</guid>
      <description>The VMware Cross vCenter VM Mobility - CLI was recently updated so I decided to try it out. In short, this little Java based application allows you to easily move or clone VMs between disparate vCenter environments.
The Fling is listed with the following requirements:
 JDK 1.7 or above
 Two vCenter instances with ESX 6.0
 Windows : Windows Server 2003 or above
 Linux : RHEL 7.x or above, Ubuntu 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere 6.5 PSOD: GP Exception 13</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vmware-vsphere-6-5-psod-gp-exception-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 08:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vmware-vsphere-6-5-psod-gp-exception-13/</guid>
      <description>While at a customer site, migrating an old vSphere 5.5 environment to 6.5, several hosts suddenly crashed with a PSOD during the migration. Long story short, we got hit by this: VMware KB 2147958: _ESXi 6.5 host fails with PSOD: GP Exception 13 in multiple VMM world at VmAnonAllocVmmPages (2147958)
It turned out that a bunch of the VMs we were vMotioning from the old environment had the cpuid.corePerSocket advanced setting set in the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi Snapshot Problems: msg.snapshot.error-QUIESCINGERROR</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/esxi-snapshot-problems-msg-snapshot-error-quiescingerror/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 13:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/esxi-snapshot-problems-msg-snapshot-error-quiescingerror/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_4559&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;] Photo by Sonja Langford[/caption]
Just a quick post about something I experienced at a client, with ESXi 6.0 hosts, today:
If you have trouble performing VMware snapshots, and see a msg.snapshot.error-QUIESCINGERROR error, check the host time settings and NTP.
In this case, snapshots of VMs located on other hosts in the cluster were fine, but once a VM was moved to the new host, snapshot operations failed after an hour or so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2016 - My takeaways</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vmworld-europe-2016-my-takeaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 23:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vmworld-europe-2016-my-takeaways/</guid>
      <description>VMworld Europe 2016 in Barcelona is a couple of weeks old now, and most of the dust has settled. Besides the general announcements around vSphere 6.5 and surrounding products, the next big thing might just be Cross-Cloud Architecture and of course VMware Cloud on AWS. The announcements around vSAN 6.5 (yes, it is now vSAN and not Virtual SAN/VSAN anymore), are also very interesting. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s time I revisit my earlier VMware VSAN; More than meets the eye post and update it for vSAN 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Server Appliance Backups</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vcenter-server-appliance-backups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 18:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vcenter-server-appliance-backups/</guid>
      <description>For some time now I&amp;rsquo;ve been advocating the usage of VCSA instead of the traditional Microsoft Windows based vCenter. It has feature parity with the Windows version now, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to deploy, gets right-sized out of the box and eliminates the need for an external Microsoft SQL server.
One of the questions I often face when talking about the appliance,_ is how do we handle backups?_ Most customers are comfortable with backup up Windows servers and Microsoft SQL, but quite a few have reservations when it comes to the integrated vPostgres database that the VCSA employs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relax and virtualize it!</title>
      <link>/virtualization/relax-and-virtualize-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 16:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/relax-and-virtualize-it/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post from Kristian Wæraas Senior Consultant Datacenter at Datametrix AS VMware VCP3/5, MCTS Hyper-V, Horizon View and Trend Micro Security Expert.
I am a curious by nature, and when my colleagues start talking frantic about some system that has crashed, I get curious and have to ask questions. Usually this ends up in me doing a lot of work.
- This, however, was not one of those times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Update Manager: Unsupported Configuration</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vmware-update-manager-unsupported-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 10:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vmware-update-manager-unsupported-configuration/</guid>
      <description>During an upgrade from vSphere 5.1 to 5.5, I ran into a rather strange issue when trying to utilize VMware Update Manager to perform the ESXi upgrade.
During scanning, VUM reported the ESXi host as &amp;ldquo;Incompatible&amp;rdquo;, without offering any other explanation. I spent ages looking through VUM logs, trying to find the culprit, suspecting it was an incompatible VIB. Without finding anything that gave me any indication on what the problem might be, I moved on to looking at the ESXi image I had imported into VUM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update ESXi Embedded Host Client Fling</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/update-esxi-embedded-host-client-fling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 16:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/update-esxi-embedded-host-client-fling/</guid>
      <description>The ESXi Embedded Host Client Fling got an upgrade today, and in addition to new features it now works properly on ESXi 5.5. In addition to this, it&amp;rsquo;s also available as an offline bundle so you can distribute it with Update Manager.
Since I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my day in esxcli, here is a quick post on how to perform the upgrade from a local http repository hosting the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi5.5 to 6.0 Upgrade From Local HTTP Daemon</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/esxi5-5-to-6-0-upgrade-from-local-http-daemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 11:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/esxi5-5-to-6-0-upgrade-from-local-http-daemon/</guid>
      <description>I was recently involved with consulting for a Norwegian shipping company who has quite a few remote vSphere installations, most of them with a couple of ESXi hosts, but no vCenter and hence no Update Manager. While looking at methods for managing these installations, in particular how to facilitate patching and upgrading scenarios, I remembered that way back in 2013, I posted Quick and Dirty HTTP-based Deployment which shows how to use the Python to run a simple http daemon, and serve files from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi Embedded Host Client</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/esxi-embedded-host-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 16:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/esxi-embedded-host-client/</guid>
      <description>I almost choked on my coffee this morning when I saw William Lam announcing a new VMware Fling called ESXi Embedded Host Client. Finally the day when we can get a local vSphere Web Client on a standalone host is here, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a moment too soon. This feature has been missing since ESX 3 and it&amp;rsquo;s VMware Infrastructure Web Access. For now, this is a Fling (which means unsupported and so on), but I really hope that this ends up being built-in to ESXi very soon &amp;ndash; even on the free vSphere Hypervisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The vSphere 6.0 Launch and The Misinformation Effect</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vsphere-6-0-launch-misinformation-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vsphere-6-0-launch-misinformation-effect/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what happens if you give 10.000 people access to an open-beta that is supposed to be under NDA?
Firstly, the NDA is no-go from the get-go. There is no way you can claim that you actually expect 10.000 people to not talk about something they know about. VMware vSpere 6.0 was the worst kept secret ever, for a reason. It might have been planned that way all along for all I know, but if that was the case, the NDA should never have been in place to begin with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing vCloud Air SSL Certificate on the vCenter Server Appliance 5.x</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/importing-vcloud-air-ssl-certificate-vcenter-server-appliance-5-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 12:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/importing-vcloud-air-ssl-certificate-vcenter-server-appliance-5-x/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m playing around a bit with vCloud Air and Virtual Private Cloud OnDemand, and in order to set up the vCloud Hybrid Service plugin in the vSphere Web Client you need to import the vCloud Air SSL certificate into vCenter. If the certificate isn&amp;rsquo;t present in the vCSA keystore when you try to authenticate with vCloud Air, you get a &amp;ldquo;Server Certificate not Verified&amp;rdquo; error, and you will be unsuccessful in configuring the plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVO:RAIL: Doing the methmath.</title>
      <link>/virtualization/hyperconvergence-meth-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 20:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/hyperconvergence-meth-math/</guid>
      <description>Howard Marks has published a post I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning do myself, but to be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m glad Howard put it out there. His is way more researched and comprehensive than mine would ever have been.
In his The True Cost Of Hyperconvergence article, Howard compares buying a new EVO:RAIL system, with building your own. Complete with the required hardware, licenses and support contracts. The result might come as a surprise to some&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Ubuntu 14.04 Appliance with VMware Studio 2.6</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/building-ubuntu-14-04-appliance-vmware-studio-2-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 23:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/building-ubuntu-14-04-appliance-vmware-studio-2-6/</guid>
      <description>VMware Studio 2.6 was released way back in March 2012, and surprisingly there seems to be no new update in sight. While VMware Studio technically still works, even with newer versions of ESXi and vCenter, the supported operating systems for the appliances it can build is somewhat outdated:
 Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.5&amp;frasl;6.0
 SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 10.2&amp;frasl;11.1
 Ubuntu 8.04.4&amp;frasl;10.04.1
 Windows Server 2003 R2 / 2008 R2 w/SP1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need the vSphere Client? VMware Has You Covered.</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vsphere-client-vmware-covered/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 21:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vsphere-client-vmware-covered/</guid>
      <description>One of the more popular posts, currently in third place, on vNinja.net is my list of vSphere Client direct download links posted back in March 2012.
Thankfully William Lam had the same idea, and got a new Knowledgebase Article published: Download URLs for VMware vSphere Client (2089791). Please use that article as the official download link documentation from now on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My VCAP-DCA 550 Experience</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vcap-dca-550-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 21:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vcap-dca-550-experience/</guid>
      <description>I finally took the plunge, and sat the VDCA550 exam yesterday. The VCAP5-DCA certification has been on my todo list way to long, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I can now tick that box and move on.
The VDCA550 exam is held in a live lab environment, with approximately 23 lab activities, which is the subsequently scored after the exam is finished. This means that you do not get an immediate pass/fail summary at the end of the exam, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be feverishly checking your email until the score report is sent to you from VMware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s official EVO:RAIL it is</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/official-evorail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 13:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/official-evorail/</guid>
      <description>VMware has finally announced what I&amp;rsquo;ve been speculating about for some time now, EVO:RAIL was announced at VMworld US this morning. Short story; It&amp;rsquo;s a HCIA (Hyper Converged Infrastructure Appliance), offered through several hardware vendors, with a new integrated management solution.
Since I&amp;rsquo;m not at VMworld my self, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the blog postings to those close to the action, but here is a quick collection of links to get you acquainted with the next EVOlution of SDDC from VMware:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s EVOlution Baby!</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/evolution-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 22:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/evolution-baby/</guid>
      <description>Finally. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found a way to put two of my favourite things together in a completely non-sensical way, namely VMware Marvin and Pearl Jam. As The Register reported earlier today, odds are that Marvin no longer responds to it&amp;rsquo;s project name, but rather to the new EVO name recently trademarked by VMware. There has been whispers of a Marvin name change for quite some time, so this isn&amp;rsquo;t really hard to believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvin Related VMworld Sessions?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/marvin-related-vmworld-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 13:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/marvin-related-vmworld-sessions/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I tried speculating on the soon-to-be-announced VMware Marvin project, but some very recent VMworld US 2014 session additions look really interesting in that regard:
SDDC1818 - VMware Customers Share Experiences and Requirements for Hyper-Converged SDDC2095 - VMware and Hyper-Converged Infrastructure SDDC1767 - SDDC at Scale with VMware Hyper-Converged Infrastructure: Deeper Dive SDDC3245-S - Software-Defined Data Center through Hyper-Converged Infrastructure
If you look at 1767 specifically, since the other sessions are still very light on details, it has a rather interesting description:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Root Cause of Invalid memory setting: memory reservation (sched.mem.min) should be equal to memsize (memsize)</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/root-invalid-memory-setting-memory-reservation-sched-mem-min-equal-memsize-memsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 10:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/root-invalid-memory-setting-memory-reservation-sched-mem-min-equal-memsize-memsize/</guid>
      <description>While working on reconfiguring my home lab setup, and migrating all the vSphere resources into a single cluster I ran into a problem powering on one of the VMs which used to run on a single host. The power on operation yielded the following error message:
Invalid memory setting: memory reservation (sched.mem.min) should be equal to memsize (memsize) [showhide type=&amp;ldquo;errorstack&amp;rdquo; more_text=&amp;ldquo;Show error stack (%s More Words)&amp;rdquo;]
  **Task Details:**         Status:    Invalid memory setting: memory reservation (sched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Marvin an Acronym?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/marvin-acronym/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 12:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/marvin-acronym/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_3213&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;164&amp;rdquo;] Marvin the Paranoid Android (HHGG)[/caption]
The recent speculations surrounding Marvin has now hit The Register (to bad they don&amp;rsquo;t link this way, but I guess thats how it is) as well, but one piece is still missing, arguably the most important one. We all know that the most important piece of something like this is it&amp;rsquo;s name, or acronym, not it&amp;rsquo;s technical merit&amp;hellip;
There has been a few attempts at guessing what Marvin is an acronym for, and here are some good ones from twitter:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX for vSphere 6.0.4 - Documentation and Download?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/nsx-vsphere-6-0-4-documentation-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 12:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/nsx-vsphere-6-0-4-documentation-download/</guid>
      <description>How long as NSX for vSphere 6.0.4 Documentation been publicly available? I just noticed this, and that the NSX downloads seem to be available via MyVMware - If you are entitled to it that is.

Does this mean it will be available for download and we get to play with it soon-ish? It might have been available earlier too, unnoticed by yours truly&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some more Marvin Speculation</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/marvin-speculation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 22:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/marvin-speculation/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_3213&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;121&amp;rdquo;]Marvin the Paranoid Android (HHGG)[/caption]
After close to a full day of Twitter speculations and discussions on what Marvin really is, some thoughts kept stuck with me, and this is my attempt at articulating what I think VMware might be up to.
_Please note that I have no real knowledge of the status of the project, nor if it really exists outside of a poster in a window in the VMware campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is VMware&#39;s Mystic Marvin Project?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vmwares-mystic-marvin-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 09:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vmwares-mystic-marvin-project/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Fletcher Cocquyt posted a rather interesting photo on his Twitter account:
This is, as far as I know, the first public sighting confirming the existence of the &amp;ldquo;mystic&amp;rdquo; project Marvin that VMware is working on. The text reads &amp;ldquo;Introducing the worlds first 100% VMware powered hyper converged infrastructure appliance.&amp;rdquo; I guess some of the VMware engineers forgot that the VMware campus get external visitors from time to time&amp;hellip;
So what is it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vShield Manager Upgrade - Password Issues</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vmware-vshield-manager-upgrade-password-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 08:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vmware-vshield-manager-upgrade-password-issues/</guid>
      <description>While upgrading a vShield Manager 5.1.1 install to 5.1.4 at a client, I ran into an issue with logging in after a completed upgrade. The username and password used to log in, and subsequently upload the upgrade file, was no longer working after the upgrade finished and the vShield Manager appliance had been rebooted.
It turns out that this was due to using international characters in the password for the admin user, in this case the Norwegian specialities æ, ø or å.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All Fun and Games Until...</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/fun-games-until/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 19:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/fun-games-until/</guid>
      <description>Remember, it&amp;rsquo;s all fun and games until someone loses a certification</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Certified Professional Recertification</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vmware-certified-professional-recertification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 12:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vmware-certified-professional-recertification/</guid>
      <description>VMware has announced a Recertification Policy for it&amp;rsquo;s VMware Certified Professional program, effective as of March 10, 2014.
In short, it means that you are no longer a VCP(x) for life, but need to recertify every 2 years, unless you take a VCAP exam during the same period. If you do not upgrade your certification, your VCP status is revoked. For all the details, have a look at Recertification Policy: VMware Certified Professional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Name Datastores in vSphere?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/automatically-datastores-vsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 16:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/automatically-datastores-vsphere/</guid>
      <description>William Lam posted &amp;ldquo;Why you should rename the default VSAN Datastore name&amp;rdquo; where he outlines why the default name for VSAN data stores should be changed. Of course, I completely agree with his views on this; Leaving it at the default might cause confusion down the line.
At the end of the post, William asks the following:
I wonder if it would be a useful to have a feature in VSAN to automatically append the vSphere Cluster name to the default VSAN Datastore name?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nordic VMUG Conference - My Thoughts</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/nordic-vmug-conference-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 23:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/nordic-vmug-conference-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday, December 3, 2013 VMware User Group Denmark arranged theNordic VMUG Conference. The event itself can only be described as a mini-VMworld, with over 600 registered attendees, and a speaker list worthy of such a nick-name.
The opening keynote was held by Joe Baguley, the closing keynote was held by Chad Sakac. In between those two, you had the possibility to attend sessions held by Cormac Hogan, Mike Laverick, Frank Brix, Paudie O-Riordan, Frank Denneman, Mattias Sundling, David Davis and Duncan Epping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vPostgres Database Backup in vCSA 5.5</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vpostgres-database-backup-vcsa-5-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 08:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vpostgres-database-backup-vcsa-5-5/</guid>
      <description>With the new vSphere 5.5 release, the VMware vCenter Appliance (vCSA) has grown up to be a viable alternative to the traditional Microsoft Windows based vCenter deployment scenario. The new vCSA version supports up to 100 hosts and 3000 (with an external Oracle database the values change to 1000&amp;frasl;10000) virtual machines, a big improvement from 5 hosts and 50 virtual machines in the previous version.
Sadly, the only external database option available for vCSA 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading vSphere vCenter Appliance 5.1 to 5.5</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/upgrading-vsphere-vcenter-appliance-5-1-5-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 12:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/upgrading-vsphere-vcenter-appliance-5-1-5-5/</guid>
      <description>In VMware KB Upgrading vCenter Server Appliance 5.0.x/5.1 to 5.5 (2058441) the procedure for upgrading an existing 5.0/5.1 vSphere vCenter Server Appliance is outlined, walking you through the steps required including deploying a new 5.5 vCSA and transferring the data from the old instance to the new one. Straight forward procedure, but there is one small caveat in this process.
One important thing to remember, and something I don´t feel that the knowledge-base article highlights well enough is that the new v5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can you combine vSphere Host Cache and vFlash on a single SSD?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/combine-vsphere-host-cache-vflash-single-ssd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/combine-vsphere-host-cache-vflash-single-ssd/</guid>
      <description>One of the new features in vSphere 5.5 is the vSphere vFlash that enables you to use a SSD/Flash device as a read cache for your storage. Duncan Epping has a series of posts on vSphere Flash Cache that is well worth a read.
vSphere vFlash caches your read IOs, but at the same time you can use it as a swap device if you run into memory contention issues. The vSphere vFlash Host Cache is similar to the older Host Cache feature, but if you are upgrading from an older version of ESXi there is a couple of things that needs to be done to be able to use this feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vCenter Server Appliance Error: VPXD must be stopped to perform this operation</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-error-vpxd-stopped-perform-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 23:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-error-vpxd-stopped-perform-operation/</guid>
      <description>While deploying a fresh vCenter Server 5.5 Appliance, I ran into an issue getting it configured.
When the appliance is deployed, the first time you log in you get presented with the configuration wizard. The wizard clearly states that if you want to set a static ip, or hostname, you should cancel the wizard, do the network configuration and then re-run the wizard after the fact.
Well, that´s what I did, and it resulted in the following error when trying to create the embedded database:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 5.5 Availability and VSAN Public Beta</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vsphere-5-5-availability-vsan-public-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 21:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vsphere-5-5-availability-vsan-public-beta/</guid>
      <description>As Eric Siebert has pointed out, the VMware vSphere release cycles are shortening.
While vSphere 5.1 could be seen as a bit rushed, especially in regards to SSO, when it was released, the shorter release cycles seem to work out pretty well.
This does make me think though; vSphere 5.5 is pretty much ready to be released to the general public, and the new VSAN component will be in a public beta at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring the ESXi Upgrade Process</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/monitoring-esxi-upgrade-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 10:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/monitoring-esxi-upgrade-process/</guid>
      <description>When doing manual host upgrades, either through the direct method or via a locally placed upgrade bundle, there is a distinct lack of progress information available after running the esxcli command.
Thankfully the ESXi host provides a running logfile of the upgrade process, which makes it much easier to keep track of what is going on and that the upgrade is indeed being performed.
The esxupdate.log is located in /var/log, and by issuing the following command in a terminal window you can have a rolling log showing you the upgrade status and progress:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centrally Disable NAT in VMware Workstation</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/centrally-disable-nat-vmware-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 08:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/centrally-disable-nat-vmware-workstation/</guid>
      <description>A fellow IT-professional, who works with the non-wired flavor of networking, contacted me with the following scenario:
A group of users, developers in this case, have VMware Workstation installed on their laptops. This makes it easy for them to manage, test and develop their applications in a closed environment without having to install a bunch of tools/services on their centrally managed laptop environment. An excellent use case for VMware Workstation if there ever was one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick and Dirty ESXi 5.1U1 Upgrade</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/quick-dirty-esxi-5-1u1-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 12:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/quick-dirty-esxi-5-1u1-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Now that VMware ESXi 5.1 Update 1 has been released I decided to do a quick and dirty upgrade of my home installation. I refuse to call it a lab these days, since it´s one singular host and all it does it contain my home domain controller&amp;hellip;
Anyway, the following procedure upgraded the host from 5.1b to 5.1U1, by downloading the upgrade directly from VMware and installing it. Make sure the host is in maintenance mode before attempting this procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brilliant idea: VMware Hosted Beta</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/brilliant-idea-vmware-hosted-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 08:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/brilliant-idea-vmware-hosted-beta/</guid>
      <description>Duncan Epping rather unceremoniously published a blog post &amp;ldquo;New Beta Program offering: VMware Hosted Beta&amp;rdquo; yesterday, outlining the availability of the new hosted beta offering that companions some of the current VMware beta programs.
_Due to the very NDA nature of the beta programs, I can´t really go into details on what is currently offered, but what I can say is this: Well done VMware!_
The VMware Hosted Beta runs on the same engine that runs the VMware Hands on Labs Online – Beta, but with a little added twist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Fling from VMware Labs: Makyo</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/fling-vmware-labs-makyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 08:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/fling-vmware-labs-makyo/</guid>
      <description>VMware Labs has released a new fling called Makyo (魔境 _makyō_ means “ghost cave” or “devil’s cave.”) which basically is a tool to copy VMs or vApps from one vCenter instance to another.
It works by doing an automated OVF export on the source vCenter, and then an import on the destination vCenter.

The plugin integrates directly into the vSphere Web Client, and I hope to see this feature installed by default in future versions of the Web Client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupported Network Configurations in Virtual Appliances</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/unsupported-network-configurations-virtual-appliances/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 23:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/unsupported-network-configurations-virtual-appliances/</guid>
      <description>My recent experience with setting up vCenter Operations Manager on a standalone ESXi host, and the always excellent William Lam´s post Automating VCSA Network Configurations For Greenfield Deployments got me thinking.
There are several other appliances out there that require deployment to a vCenter, to be able to configure the networking options and not just default to DHCP. In many, and perhaps even most, cases you can work around that by running the _vami_set_network _command to change from DHCP to STATIC network configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purging the vCenter Operations Manager 5.x Database</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/purging-vcenter-operations-manager-5-x-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 12:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/purging-vcenter-operations-manager-5-x-database/</guid>
      <description>A client of mine recently had their vCenter 5.0 appliance replaced with a new vCenter 5.1 appliance, something vCenter Operations Manager did not enjoy. In this case the original vCenter 5.0 Appliance was turned shut down, a new 5.1 Appliance deployed, with the same IP as the old one, and then configured. Naturally the existing hosts were added to the fresh vCenter, clusters recreated and in general everything was reconfigured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Mr. Herrod</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/goodbye-mr-herrod/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/goodbye-mr-herrod/</guid>
      <description>SearchserverVirtualization published an article today called &amp;ldquo;Experts weigh in on CTO Herrod&amp;rsquo;s departure, future of VMware&amp;rdquo; where I have been quoted in regard toSteve Herrod&amp;rsquo;s departure from VMware.
While the quote itself is correct, I feel that there is a need to further expand on what I said, in the context it was given in.
So here it is, my entire response:
My reaction to Steve Herrods departure is probably on par with just about everyone else&#39;s, one of surprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Operations Manager and vCenter Deployment Dependency</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vcenter-operations-manager-vcenter-deployment-dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 21:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vcenter-operations-manager-vcenter-deployment-dependency/</guid>
      <description>In order to be able to deploy vCenter Operations Manager, the ESXi host it is deployed to needs to be managed by a vCenter. At first glance, that seems like a fair and pretty straight forward requirement, right? But, is it?
While I can see the need for a vCenter in the environment that vCenter Operations Manager is supposed to monitor, I don´t understand why the host you want to deploy the vApp on has to be managed by a vCenter instance as well?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Hands-on Lab Online Public Beta Review</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vmware-hands-on-lab-online-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 18:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vmware-hands-on-lab-online-review/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago VMware announced Project Nee, something I was, and still am, pretty excited about.
This afternoon I finally got access to the Hands-on Labs Online Beta part of Project Nee, and I have to say, this looks incredibly promising and useful.
At the moment, the available labs are:Cloud Infrastructure:  HOL-INF-02 - Explore vSphere 5.1 Distributed Switch (vDS) New Features This lab explores the new features of the vSphere Distributed Switch (vDS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere Health Check - What´s in it for You?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vmware-vsphere-health-checks-wha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 22:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vmware-vsphere-health-checks-wha/</guid>
      <description>VMware vSphere Health Check is a service provided by VMware Professional Services, either by their own consultants or by a consultant from a VMware Certified Solution Provider.
I´m lucky enough to be employed by a Premier VMware Solution Provider who offers this service to our customers, and I´ve completed a fair number of these health checks in the last couple of months.
You might ask what the value of the Health Check is, and for the end customer it´s pretty clear cut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIP VCP Club 2012</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vip-vcp-club-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 09:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vip-vcp-club-2012/</guid>
      <description>VMware Norway held their first ever _VIP VCP Club_ yesterday in Oslo.
**What is VIP VCP Club? ** This a new concept by VMware Norway, for certified VMware professionals, where the idea is to gather local certified VMware Professionals for a day of hands-on labs, specialized technical sessions and general community building.
Agenda: [caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_2216&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;] Lee Dilworth
Juggling for the Crowd[/caption]
 **Storage/HA/DR/Clustering **Presented by Lee Dilworth</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Did the HP BL460c G8 Lose It&#39;s Datastore?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/hp-bl460c-g8-lose-its-datastore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 21:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/hp-bl460c-g8-lose-its-datastore/</guid>
      <description>Post Update: As per Preetam´s comment, HP has published a customer advisory regarding the usage of install vs update.
After installing a couple of brand new HP ProLiant BL460c G8 blades with HP Smart Array P220i controllers at a customer site, I decided that I should upgrade from the VMware-ESXi-5.0.0-Update1-623860-HP-5.20.43.iso Build 623860 used to install the blades, to the latest 821926 build offered by VMware.
Normally this is a really easy process using VMware Update Manager, but since this is a new installation all the prerequisites for that are not in place just yet and I decided to use esxcli to perform the update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want Access to the VMworld 2012 Sessions?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/access-vmworld-2012-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 16:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/access-vmworld-2012-sessions/</guid>
      <description>Fellow vExpert Rick Scherer is giving away a voucher that provides free access to all of the VMworld 2012 sessions, including associated MP3′s and PDF’s.
Have a look at his post Win Access to VMworld 2012 Sessions and enter to win now!
Good stuff Rick, real good!
Update October 30th:
Fresh VCDX and fellow vExpert Joep Piscaer has followed suit and announced his own &amp;ldquo;Want to win a VMworld 2012 Subscription?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vShield Endpoint Entitlement, not just for vSphere 5.1</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vshield-endpoint-entitlement-vsphere-5-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 21:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vshield-endpoint-entitlement-vsphere-5-1/</guid>
      <description>When VMware vSphere 5.1 and vCloud Networking and Security 5.1 was launched at VMworld US in late August, one of the news items was the change in licensing relating to vShield Endpoint.
vShield Endpoint is now included in every vSphere edition, with the exception of the lowest tier vSphere Essentials package.
I was under the impression that you had to upgrade to the new 5.1 version to take advantage of the licensing change, and get licenses available for vShield Endpoint, but a new VMware Knowledgebase article named KB: 2036875 Downloading and enabling vShield Endpoint on supported vSphere platforms debunks that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting It Right: VMware Training and Certification</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/right-vmware-training-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 21:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/right-vmware-training-certification/</guid>
      <description>Everyone, and probably their extended family including their mother-in-law, has heard me whine and complain about the VCP training requirements.
VMware has unveiled a new lab, namely Project Nee (Next-Generation Education Environment)
and this is something I´m really excited about.
Project Nee is described as this:
VMware Project NEE is a new VMware Labs project providing a richly featured, powerful online learning and lab environment delivered from the cloud to any device, anywhere, anytime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESXi 4 vs ESXi 5 Log File Locations</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vmware-esxi-4-vs-esxi-5-log-file-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vmware-esxi-4-vs-esxi-5-log-file-locations/</guid>
      <description>This post is inspired by a tweet from Andrew Storrs, where he pinpoints that the host log file locations have changed between ESXi 4 and ESXi 5.
Note: This post has been updated with new log files for ESXi 5.1
ESXi 4 Log File Locations: [table id=6 /]
ESXi 5 Log File Locations: [table id=5 /]
Between version 5.0 and 5.1 the log file locations have not changed, but a couple of new logs have been added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verifying VMware Downloads</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/verifying-vmware-downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 21:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/verifying-vmware-downloads/</guid>
      <description>Now that vSphere 5.1 and assorted products have been released into the wild, how do you check the integrity of your downloaded file? As you might be aware of, VMware publishes both MD5 and SHA1 hashes for their files, making it possible to check if the file you just downloaded is identical to the file offered from VMware.
Checking the MD5 or SHA1 hash for a single file is easy, at least in OS X where you don´t need any third party tools to check.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 minute lightning Tech Talk at VMworld?</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/techtalks-at-vmworld2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 17:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/techtalks-at-vmworld2012/</guid>
      <description>I love it when a plan comes together, especially when someone gets an idea and then someone fires on all cylinders and executes!
As mentioned before, there has been a lot of talk about various ways to create a &amp;ldquo;soapbox&amp;rdquo; for all those who submitted VMworld sessions and got rejected, or those who did not submit but would still like to present.
Thankfully the guys behind vBrownBags has teamed up with VMware communities and are now offering this opportunity at VMworld 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Session Reject Club</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vmworld-session-reject-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 00:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vmworld-session-reject-club/</guid>
      <description>**VMworld Session Reject Club 1st RULE: You do talk about Reject Club. **
Today VMware has sent out notifications to VMworld 2012 session submitters, with a yay or nay email. Of course, this sparked a lot of conversation on Twitter, and Scott Lowe published a blog post proposing a VMworld Unconference, and exploring several options:
 A physical “unconference”
 A virtual “unconference”
 A series of 10-minute “flash talks” at VMworld 2012</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinapped vSphere Client Updated to V5.0</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/thinapped-vsphere-client-updated-v5-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 11:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/thinapped-vsphere-client-updated-v5-0/</guid>
      <description>The Thinapped vSphere Client has finally been updated to v5.0, and is readily available for download!
Sadly the new version is v5.0 only, and will only allow you to connect to vSphere v5 hosts and since the new release has replaced the old release on the VMware Fling website, you´re out of luck if you haven´t already got the 4.0 version stowed away in your own private locker.
I hope VMware decides to either make the 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCDX Wannabe goes live</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vcdx-wannabe-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 08:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vcdx-wannabe-live/</guid>
      <description>My little pet project VCDX Wannabe has now (finally) gone live. For now it´s mostly a collection of links and resources, but that will change over time.
So, if you want to see me (and possibly a few others) either go down in flames, kicking and screaming, or succeed obtaining the VCDX certification you now have the opportunity to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Client Download URLs</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vcenter-client-download-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 12:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vcenter-client-download-urls/</guid>
      <description>Since the vCenter Client no longer is bundled with an ESXi host installation, I´ve compiled a quick list of direct download URLs for the most recent clients.
Update 17th September 2014: VMware has published the official list in knowledge base article KB2089791, use that as the official list going forward.
Remember, the client download URL is still available from the vCenter server, if you point your browser to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Virtual Customer Labs</title>
      <link>/news/vmware-virtual-customer-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 18:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/news/vmware-virtual-customer-labs/</guid>
      <description>I´ve mentioned this earlier, VMware hands-in labs going public in 2012, but finally it seems like something is happening in that regard!
Scott Sauer has announced the availability of &amp;ldquo;VMware Virtual Customer Labs” (vCL) where he walks us through the setup and delivery of the new vCL offering.
At the moment it´s only available to &amp;ldquo;selected customers&amp;rdquo;, supported by a VMware pre-sales engineer, and the number of labs are limited. It´s still a work in progress, and I´m sure great things will come out of this!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCP 5 Certification Requirements Clarification</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/vcp-5-certification-requirement-clarification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 20:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/vcp-5-certification-requirement-clarification/</guid>
      <description>In a recent article, VCP 5 certification course deadline looms over VMware pros both vNinja.net contributors (Christian and Ed) are quoted in relation to the VCP 5 certification upgrade deadline of February 29th 2012.
While I can´t speak for Ed, I can clarify my own comments a bit. The following is a quote from VMware, taken from the article in question:
“That requirement is in place to maintain the integrity of the certification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and Using a Virtual Floppy in vSphere</title>
      <link>/virtualization/creating-virtual-floppy-vsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 22:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/creating-virtual-floppy-vsphere/</guid>
      <description>My new colleague Olav Tvedt asked me if I could test his method of enabling Bitlocker in a VM, on VMware vSphere. Of course, I was happy to oblige.
I followed the same steps as he did in his Running Bitlocker on a Virtual computer post, and it worked perfectly.
The only real difference between doing this in Hyper-V and on ESXi, is that the virtual floppy drive on ESXi by default doesn&amp;rsquo;t emulate an empty floppy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Installation and Configuring of vSphere ESXi 5</title>
      <link>/virtualization/auto-installation-and-configuring-of-vsphere-esxi-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 23:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/auto-installation-and-configuring-of-vsphere-esxi-5/</guid>
      <description>One of the last projects I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with at Seatrans, is to automate the installation and configuration of vSphere ESXi 5 hosts for deployment on vessels. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked a bit about this before, both on vSoup and in Setting Up Automated ESXi Deployments where I outlined my PXE and PowerCLI based installation and configuration scheme. Not much has changed since then, except updating the PXE server to offer ESXi 5, instead of ESXi 4 and a lot of work has been put into the scripting, including a front-end GUI for the PowerCLI script itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing VMware vSphere 5 Swap to Host Cache</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/testing-vmware-vsphere-5-swap-to-host-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 22:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/testing-vmware-vsphere-5-swap-to-host-cache/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago I fitted a small 64GB SSD disk to my HP MicroServer just to have a quick look at the new vSphere 5 feature Swap to Host Cache, where vSphere 5 reclaims memory by storing the swapped out pages in the host cache on a solid-state drive. Naturally, this is a lot faster than swapping to non-SSD storage, but you will still see a performance hit when this happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Horizon Application Manager Now and Beyond</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vmware-horizon-application-manager-now-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 23:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vmware-horizon-application-manager-now-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>VMware has announced Horizon Application Manager 1.2, and together with the new ThinApp 4.7 release it promises &amp;ldquo;end users access to Windows, SaaS and enterprise web applications across different devices while retaining control and visibility via policy-driven management&amp;rdquo;.
VMware Horizon Application Manager now manages your ThinApp applications making it easier and faster to provide virtualized Windows applications to end users. From Horizon Administration, you can deploy ThinApp packages, entitle users and groups, track user licenses, and manage application updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMTN Subscription</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vmtn-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 09:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vmtn-subscription/</guid>
      <description>Mike Laverick has started something of a petition to bring back the VMTN Subscription option, and I could not agree more!
The VMTN Subscription was a way for interested parties to pay for a years subscription to VMware products, akin to the Microsoft Technet subscription program. It&amp;rsquo;s not intended for production use, but as a means to get hold of products for lab work, testing and development.
I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why VMware pulled the plug on that option back in 2007, but I do understand why it&amp;rsquo;s time to bring it back to life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Can&#39;t I Syslog my VMware ESXi Installation?</title>
      <link>/virtualization/why-cant-i-syslog-my-vmware-esxi-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 22:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/why-cant-i-syslog-my-vmware-esxi-installation/</guid>
      <description>Juan Manuel Rey&amp;rsquo;s post Monitor ESX 4.x to ESXi 5.0 migration process show how you can watch the progress of an ESX 4 to ESXi 5 upgrade procedure, by looking at the live logs.
While this is very useful, and in many cases a real learning experience, it got me thinking that these logs should be available remotely as well. Since ESXi supports, and actively encourages, the use of an external Syslog service for log file safekeeping and monitoring, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t the installation logs for ESXi also be logged externally if configured?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Simulation in VMware Workstation 8</title>
      <link>/virtualization/network-simulation-in-vmware-workstation-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 09:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/network-simulation-in-vmware-workstation-8/</guid>
      <description>In the new VMware Workstation 8 release, VMware has added a rudimentary network simulation setting where you can tweak bandwidth and packet loss for a given network card. Very useful when testing applications and servers and want to know how they react to network issues, or if you want to simulate a WAN link. I know this was available in Workstation 7 as well, but it used to be a team feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Workstation 8 - What&#39;s new?</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vmware-workstation-8-whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 12:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vmware-workstation-8-whats-new/</guid>
      <description>VMware is close (still in beta) to releasing the new major release of VMware Workstation.
Update 14. September 2011: VMware Workstation 8 has now officially been released.
VMware Workstation 8 brings a lot of new features and enhancements to the table, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough to play around with it in the beta program.
VMware Workstation 8 System Requirements To be able to install VMware Workstation, the host system processor needs to meet the following requirements:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Hands-on Labs going public in 2012</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vmworld-hands-on-labs-going-public-in-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 10:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vmworld-hands-on-labs-going-public-in-2012/</guid>
      <description>VMware Labs now has fixed data centers which means that the VMworld Hands-On labs are going to be publicly available in early 20112!
Hear Mornay Van Der Walt, Senior Director R&amp;amp;D at VMware, explain the details in this video from VMworld TV:
This is great news, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who thinks this is a really good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMFS-5: Block Size Me</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vmfs-5-block-size-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 12:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vmfs-5-block-size-me/</guid>
      <description>The up and coming release of VMware vSphere 5 comes with an upgraded versjon of the VMware vStorage VMFS volume file system. One of the problems with VMFS-3 an earlier is that the block size you define when you format the datastore, determines the maximum size of the VMDK files stored on it. This means that when planning your datastore infrastructure you must have an idea on how large your VMDK files will potentially be during the lifecycle of the datastore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear John</title>
      <link>/virtualization/dear-john/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 22:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/dear-john/</guid>
      <description>No, this is not a farewell post, but rather the opposite. It&amp;rsquo;s Dr John Troyer&amp;rsquo;s birthday!
John lives and breathes his role, as Senior Social Media Strategist at VMware, and I have to say that one of the most brilliant moves VMware has done is to employ John in his current role. Lots of other corporation employ marketing people in their social media roles, VMware went the other way and put the very technically savvy Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 5 and new licensing - Good or bad?</title>
      <link>/news/vsphere-5-and-new-licensing-good-or-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 18:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/news/vsphere-5-and-new-licensing-good-or-bad/</guid>
      <description>As many of you did I watched todays Cloud Infrastructure Forum and the release of vSphere 5 today. I was very excited with many of the features such as Storage Profiling, Storage DRS, VMFS 5 release, and they have blown the top off of the resource limits on VMs to create Monster VMs - just to mention a few. However, one topic I notice causing quite a stir is the new licensing that seemed to be very briefly mentioned at the end of the webinar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Event: Raising the Bar, Part V</title>
      <link>/virtualization/online-event-raising-the-bar-part-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 09:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/online-event-raising-the-bar-part-v/</guid>
      <description>July 12, 2011 9am-Noon Pacific Time: Join this online event, and get all the details on &amp;ldquo;the next generation of cloud infrastructure&amp;rdquo;!
VMware CEO Paul Maritz and CTO Steve Herrod will be presenting on the next generation of cloud infrastructure. Join us and experience how the virtualization journey is helping transform IT and ushering in the era of Cloud Computing. 9:00-9:45 Paul and Steve present - live online streaming 10:00-12:00 three tracks of deep dive breakout sessions 10:00-12:00 live Q&amp;A with VMware cloud and virtualization experts  Register for the event now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Automated ESXi Deployments</title>
      <link>/virtualization/setting-up-automated-esxi-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 08:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/setting-up-automated-esxi-deployments/</guid>
      <description>Automating ESXi installs was made much easier after the release of vSphere 4.1 where the Scripted Install feature was added, and by using VMware Auto Deploy from VMware Labs. VMware Auto Deploy requires that you have vCenter and Host Profiles in your environment, and that again requires that you have Enterprise Plus licenses in your environment.
It is, however, possible to deploy ESXi in an automated fashion completely without vCenter and Host Profiles!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>