<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maintenance on My blog</title>
    <link>/tags/maintenance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maintenance on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>yourname@example.com (yourname)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yourname@example.com (yourname)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Copyright my blog</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 10:34:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/maintenance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring the ESXi Upgrade Process</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/monitoring-esxi-upgrade-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 10:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/vmware-2/monitoring-esxi-upgrade-process/</guid>
      <description>When doing manual host upgrades, either through the direct method or via a locally placed upgrade bundle, there is a distinct lack of progress information available after running the esxcli command.
Thankfully the ESXi host provides a running logfile of the upgrade process, which makes it much easier to keep track of what is going on and that the upgrade is indeed being performed.
The esxupdate.log is located in /var/log, and by issuing the following command in a terminal window you can have a rolling log showing you the upgrade status and progress:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and configuring VMware vCenter Operations</title>
      <link>/virtualization/installing-and-configuring-vmware-vcenter-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 19:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/installing-and-configuring-vmware-vcenter-operations/</guid>
      <description>VMware vCenter Operations was released to the general public a week or so ago and is available for download right now. As usual you can download a 60 day trial, and get started immediately.
Like other recent management utilities from VMware, vCenter Operations comes in the form of a .OVF template (like vCMA/vMA).
Installing VMware vCenter Operations Download VMware vCenter Operations and import by starting vCenter Client, navigate to the “File” menu and select “Deploy OVF template…”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Admins - Virtual Pirates?</title>
      <link>/virtualization/virtual-admins-virtual-pirates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 22:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/virtual-admins-virtual-pirates/</guid>
      <description>When Rich Brambley posted &amp;laquo;A Pirate Invented Server Virtualization&amp;raquo; today, it reminded me of a little story from my own production environment.
This story is a couple of years old, but sadly it&amp;rsquo;s still valid. A very specialized application that we run, requires a SQL Server Express instance, a proxy/licensing server and client installation with license files to work. This application isn&amp;rsquo;t very advanced, nor very resource intensive so by nature it&amp;rsquo;s prime for running in a virtualized environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter 4.1 Database Recovery Model Defaults</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vcenter-4-1-database-recovery-model-defaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 21:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vcenter-4-1-database-recovery-model-defaults/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes leaving the defaults in place might just come back and bite you, hard.
That might also be the case with your vCenter 4.1 database, as I experienced back in July.
All of a sudden my vCenter Server stopped working. The symptoms where pretty obvious, my client couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect to the vCenter server. Naturally I connected to the server, and noticed that the VMware VirtualCenter Server services had indeed stopped. No wonder the client couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P2V a Domain Controller? Why would you?</title>
      <link>/virtualization/p2v-a-domain-controller-why-would-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 19:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/p2v-a-domain-controller-why-would-you/</guid>
      <description>Some topics seem to pop up at random intervals, one of them being virtualizing Microsoft Active Directory Domain Controller servers. The question is often either &amp;laquo;Should I virtualize my Domain Controllers, and if so should I virtualize all of them?&amp;raquo; or &amp;laquo;Should I do a P2V (Physical 2 Virtual) conversion of my existing Domain Controllers, or create new ones?&amp;laquo;
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about the second question. While there is a lot to be said about the first one as well, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that for future post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Server 4.1 Performance and Best Practices</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vcenter-server-4-1-performance-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 20:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vcenter-server-4-1-performance-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>VMware has published a new whitepaper called VMware vCenter Server Performance and Best Practices.
This is a must read if you manage a vCenter 4.1 installation, or are currently planning your upgrade.
The whitepaper highlights the performance improvements in the latest version, sizing guidelines, best practices and some really good real world information from several case studies. One simple, but probably often overlooked tip, is that the amount of vCenter Clients connected to your vCenter Server has an impact on it&amp;rsquo;s performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating your vCenter from 32bit to 64bit</title>
      <link>/virtualization/migrating-your-vcenter-from-32bit-to-64bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 12:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/migrating-your-vcenter-from-32bit-to-64bit/</guid>
      <description>As you may or may not know, the new vCenter 4.1 requires that the host it runs on is 64 bit. As 4.0 and previous versions weren&amp;rsquo;t supported on 64 bit at all, this probably means that when you upgrade you will need to move your existing database to a new host.
There are several ways of doing the migration, but one way is to backup your existing database, and restore it on a new host and point the new vCenter 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>