<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflow on My blog</title>
    <link>/tags/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflow on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>yourname@example.com (yourname)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yourname@example.com (yourname)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Copyright my blog</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 13:47:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Pocket with Todoist via IFTTT</title>
      <link>/workflow/integrating-pocket-with-todoist-via-ifttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 13:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/workflow/integrating-pocket-with-todoist-via-ifttt/</guid>
      <description>Myles Gray asked me how I integrate Pocket with Todoist, after my How I use Todoist post, and the answer is very simple: IFTTT. If-This-Then-That lets you connect services, and create rules (or applets) that trigger based on events in those services, luckily both Todoist and Pocket are supported.
Now, there is a bit of overlap between how I use Pocket and Todoist, but I mainly use Pocket to keep track of links I want to either read later, or use as basis for blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I use Todoist</title>
      <link>/workflow/how-i-use-todoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/workflow/how-i-use-todoist/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before, I use Todoist to keep track of my personal to-do list. This is the first to-do manager I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to stick with, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it daily for well over 2 years now. In that two year period I&amp;rsquo;ve reorganised it a bit, but for the most part I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to keep to the main structure I initially created when setting it up the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you ChangeLog?</title>
      <link>/workflow/changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 10:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/workflow/changelog/</guid>
      <description>In my work as a consultant I often have many small tasks to perform for customers, all while completing a bigger project. I have found that an easy way to keep track of all the little and big changes, is to create a ChangeLog. Normally ChangeLog&amp;rsquo;s are referenced in development projects, but it also sense to use it to track of your own, or your team members, changes to an infrastructure environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown All the Things!</title>
      <link>/virtualization/markdown-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 23:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/markdown-things/</guid>
      <description>Obviously I&amp;rsquo;m a bit late to the party here, but I guess late is better than never. It recently dawned on me that mucking about with lots of different file formats, interfaces and ways of doing things is rather counterproductive.
A lot of my work these days are related to generating content, be it a simple blog post like this or writing customer proposals and documentation. In the end, the deliverables are often quite different, but at the core they are strangely enough very similar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>