<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vcp on Adventures in Hugo</title>
    <link>/tags/vcp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vcp on Adventures in Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Christian Mohn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 19:43:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/vcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All Fun and Games Until...</title>
      <link>/posts/fun-games-until/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 19:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/fun-games-until/</guid>
      <description>Remember, it&amp;rsquo;s all fun and games until someone loses a certification</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Certified Professional Recertification</title>
      <link>/posts/vmware-certified-professional-recertification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 12:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/vmware-certified-professional-recertification/</guid>
      <description>VMware has announced a Recertification Policy for it&amp;rsquo;s VMware Certified Professional program, effective as of March 10, 2014.
In short, it means that you are no longer a VCP(x) for life, but need to recertify every 2 years, unless you take a VCAP exam during the same period. If you do not upgrade your certification, your VCP status is revoked. For all the details, have a look at Recertification Policy: VMware Certified Professional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Microsoft really be Fair and Balanced?</title>
      <link>/posts/microsoft-fair-balanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 23:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/microsoft-fair-balanced/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has launched Virtualization2, a program to educate VMware administrators on Hyper-V and the System Center suite of tools. In short, these arefree online training sessiosn on November 19th and 20th, that also comes with a voucher for their new Microsoft virtualization certification exam (74-409).
This comes in addition to their existing Microsoft Virtualization for VMware Professionals Jump Start training course.
I think this is a good idea, and if you are able to close your eyes to the hyperbole, and disregard things like &amp;ldquo;Microsoft Wants to Help VMware Experts “Future-Proof “ Their Career&amp;rdquo;, I applaud this initiative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIP VCP Club 2012</title>
      <link>/posts/vip-vcp-club-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 09:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/vip-vcp-club-2012/</guid>
      <description>VMware Norway held their first ever _VIP VCP Club_ yesterday in Oslo.
**What is VIP VCP Club? ** This a new concept by VMware Norway, for certified VMware professionals, where the idea is to gather local certified VMware Professionals for a day of hands-on labs, specialized technical sessions and general community building.
Agenda: [caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_2216&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;] Lee Dilworth
Juggling for the Crowd[/caption]
 **Storage/HA/DR/Clustering **Presented by Lee Dilworth</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCP 5 Certification Requirements Clarification</title>
      <link>/posts/vcp-5-certification-requirement-clarification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 20:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/vcp-5-certification-requirement-clarification/</guid>
      <description>In a recent article, VCP 5 certification course deadline looms over VMware pros both vNinja.net contributors (Christian and Ed) are quoted in relation to the VCP 5 certification upgrade deadline of February 29th 2012.
While I can´t speak for Ed, I can clarify my own comments a bit. The following is a quote from VMware, taken from the article in question:
“That requirement is in place to maintain the integrity of the certification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>