<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Todoist on My blog</title>
    <link>/tags/todoist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Todoist on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>yourname@example.com (yourname)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yourname@example.com (yourname)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Copyright my blog</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 13:47:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/todoist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Pocket with Todoist via IFTTT</title>
      <link>/workflow/integrating-pocket-with-todoist-via-ifttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 13:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/workflow/integrating-pocket-with-todoist-via-ifttt/</guid>
      <description>Myles Gray asked me how I integrate Pocket with Todoist, after my How I use Todoist post, and the answer is very simple: IFTTT. If-This-Then-That lets you connect services, and create rules (or applets) that trigger based on events in those services, luckily both Todoist and Pocket are supported.
Now, there is a bit of overlap between how I use Pocket and Todoist, but I mainly use Pocket to keep track of links I want to either read later, or use as basis for blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I use Todoist</title>
      <link>/workflow/how-i-use-todoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/workflow/how-i-use-todoist/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before, I use Todoist to keep track of my personal to-do list. This is the first to-do manager I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to stick with, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it daily for well over 2 years now. In that two year period I&amp;rsquo;ve reorganised it a bit, but for the most part I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to keep to the main structure I initially created when setting it up the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Todoist: One year later</title>
      <link>/workflow/todoist-one-year-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 13:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/workflow/todoist-one-year-later/</guid>
      <description>A little over a year ago I posted Combining Todoist and Evernote, because awesome and I thought it was about time to post a follow up now one year later.
Evernote: Firstly, my Evernote is still a giant mess, just as it was a year ago. I have lots of data in Evernote, but it&amp;rsquo;s main purpose is just storing quick notes on ongoing projects and it serves as a basis for generating proper documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining Todoist and Evernote, because awesome</title>
      <link>/workflow/combining-todoist-evernote-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 16:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/workflow/combining-todoist-evernote-awesome/</guid>
      <description>A while back I declared Evernote bankruptcy, even if I managed to misspell it while doing so:
That&#39;s it, I&#39;m declaring [@evernote](https://twitter.com/evernote) bankrupcy. — Christian Mohn™ (@h0bbel) [May 22, 2014](https://twitter.com/h0bbel/status/469455493631860736)  The thing is, I really want to use Evernote in a proper and organised manner. The problem is; I was completely unable to do so, mostly since I had no clear idea on the how, the when and the why back when I started using it many moons ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>