<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on Adventures in Hugo</title>
    <link>/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on Adventures in Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Christian Mohn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 10:38:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I use Todoist</title>
      <link>/workflow/how-i-use-todoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workflow/how-i-use-todoist/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before, I use Todoist to keep track of my personal to-do list. This is the first to-do manager I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to stick with, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it daily for well over 2 years now. In that two year period I&amp;rsquo;ve reorganised it a bit, but for the most part I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to keep to the main structure I initially created when setting it up the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if it&#39;s Just Some Crazy Guy in a Clown Suit?</title>
      <link>/news/what-if-its-just-some-crazy-guy-in-a-clown-suit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 21:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/what-if-its-just-some-crazy-guy-in-a-clown-suit/</guid>
      <description>As a few of you have noticed, I recently changed my title on LinkedIn from Chief Consultant to Cloud Architect in the newly formed EVRY Cloud Consulting division, but what does that mean and perhaps more importantly, why?
The closest description I have found to describe what my new role is this:
 Leads in the development of the technical solution or offering, in translating the business needs into technical requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Personal vMotion</title>
      <link>/news/my-personal-vmotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 09:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/my-personal-vmotion/</guid>
      <description>Every  once in a while an opportunity presents itself that is just too good to pass up and after 8 years at Seatrans AS I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move on and and accept a position as a Senior Consultant in the Infrastructure Consulting division of EDB ErgoGroup.
Seatrans has been a fantastic employer, and without the backing and support I&amp;rsquo;ve had over the years I would not be in a position where this change would be possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>