<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Veeam on My blog</title>
    <link>/tags/veeam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Veeam on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>yourname@example.com (yourname)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yourname@example.com (yourname)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Copyright my blog</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 16:45:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/veeam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar: Veeam integration with VMware vSAN, vSphere tags and SPBM policies</title>
      <link>/virtualization/webinar-veeam-integration-with-vmware-vsan-vsphere-tags-and-spbm-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 16:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/webinar-veeam-integration-with-vmware-vsan-vsphere-tags-and-spbm-policies/</guid>
      <description>Warning: Shameless self promotion ahead!
November 30th I&amp;rsquo;ll be joining Martin Plesner-Jacobsen from Veeam for a Live Webinar: _Veeam integration with VMware vSAN, vSphere tags and SPBM policies. _
Now that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of goodies in one place!

Click on the banner above to register now, and reserve your spot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VeeamOn Tour Virtual 2017 - Reserve your spot!</title>
      <link>/virtualization/veeamon-tour-virtual-2017-reserve-your-spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 10:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/veeamon-tour-virtual-2017-reserve-your-spot/</guid>
      <description>Veeam is hosting their VeeamOn Tour Virtual 2017 event on December 5th, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be part of the panel of bloggers in the Expert Lounge!
Veeam describes the event like this:
The biggest online Availability event in EMEA — VeeamON Tour Virtual 2017 — is once again coming to your desktop! No need to leave your chair — Experience Availability simply by joining us for an ultimate digital journey! VeeamON Tour Virtual runs from 11 am to 5 pm CET, and offers three separate tracks; Business, Technical and Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam vCenter Migration Utility</title>
      <link>/virtualization/veeam-vcenter-migration-utility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 09:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/veeam-vcenter-migration-utility/</guid>
      <description>Way back in 2013, I published Preserve your Veeam B&amp;amp;R Backups Jobs when Moving vCenter, outlining how to &amp;laquo;cheat&amp;raquo; (by using a CNAME alias) to preserve your Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication jobs if you replace your VMware vCenter.
Naturally, when there is a new vCenter instance, all the Virtual Machine Managed Object Reference&amp;rsquo;s (MoRef) change, which makes Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication start a new backup/replication chain, since all VMs are treated as new ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Vanguard 2015</title>
      <link>/virtualization/veeam-vanguard-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 13:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/veeam-vanguard-2015/</guid>
      <description>Veeam has been &amp;laquo;silently&amp;raquo; working on their own global influencer program, and the inaugural list of Veeam Vanguards was published today. I am thrilled to be selected amongst the first 31 people awarded this title, it&amp;rsquo;s quite an exclusive list!
So what&amp;rsquo;s up with the name? Well, here is one of the definitions of vanguard I found:
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;vanguard&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;ˈvanɡɑːd/&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; noun a group of people leading the way in new developments or ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Backup &amp; Replication 8: RPC error:Access is denied Fix</title>
      <link>/virtualization/veeam-backup-replication-8-rpc-erroraccess-denied-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 22:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/veeam-backup-replication-8-rpc-erroraccess-denied-fix/</guid>
      <description>I recently set up a new Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication v8 demo lab, and my intial small job that consisted of two different Linux VMs and one Windows Server 2012 R2 Domain Controller was chugging along nicely. I had one minor from the start though, and that was that file indexing consistently failed for the Windows VM. No big deal, but I thought it was strange at the time. After all, the Linux VMs were indexed just fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Veeam Backup &amp; Replication for VMware vSphere Book Winners</title>
      <link>/news/learning-veeam-backup-replication-vmware-vsphere-book-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 09:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/news/learning-veeam-backup-replication-vmware-vsphere-book-winners/</guid>
      <description>Packt Publishing has picked three lucky winners for the Veeam® Backup &amp;amp; Replication for VMware vSphere book.
The winners are as follows, with the winning comments:
Chris Childerhose:
Wow nice to see a book come out for Veeam. Look forward to the following things from this book to help better my Veeam skills - Install and manage a Veeam® Backup &amp; Replication v7 infrastructure Discover how to back up and restore data in virtual environments Utilize WAN acceleration to speed up backup to remote locations Understand what options are available for Veeam® Backup &amp; Replication, and how to configure these options These topics will help further my skills with Veeam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win Free e-copies of Learning Veeam® Backup &amp; Replication for VMware vSphere</title>
      <link>/book/win-free-e-copies-learning-veeam-backup-replication-vmware-vsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 08:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/book/win-free-e-copies-learning-veeam-backup-replication-vmware-vsphere/</guid>
      <description>Update: The contest is now closed, and I have forwarded all comments to Packt Publishing, and they will contact the winners directly. Thanks to everyone who entered!
I have teamed up with Packt Publishing to organize a giveaway of my new Veeam® Backup &amp;amp; Replication for VMware vSphere book.
3 lucky winners stand a chance to win e-copies of their new book. Keep reading to find out how you can be one of them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Webinar &amp; NFR Licenses</title>
      <link>/virtualization/veeam-webinar-nfr-licenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 15:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/veeam-webinar-nfr-licenses/</guid>
      <description>This coming tuesday the first ever Veeam Webinar held in Norwegian will be held by yours truly. Feel free to sign up now and listen to me speak for an hour or so.

Also, Veeam is continuing it´s support of the virtualization community and is yet again offering free 180-days Veeam Backup Management Suite v7 NFR licenses for VMware and Hyper-V.
Note that this offer is only available to anyone who is one of the following: VMware vExpert, VMware Certified Professional (VCP), Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP), Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS) and Most Valuable Professional (MVP)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backing up vCenter DB with Veeam B&amp;R 6.5</title>
      <link>/virtualization/backing-up-vcenter-db-with-veeam-br-6-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 09:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/backing-up-vcenter-db-with-veeam-br-6-5/</guid>
      <description>It´s a well known problem that with Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Recovery Replication 6.5, and earlier, backing up the SQL server that hosts the vCenter DB poses a problem. KB1051 VSS for vCenter outlines the issue well, and provides a workaround.
If you experience this problem, you will see entries like this in your Veeam B&amp;amp;R backup logs:
[caption id=&amp;laquo;attachment_2490&amp;raquo; align=&amp;laquo;aligncenter&amp;raquo; width=&amp;laquo;640&amp;raquo;] Veeam vCenterDB Backup Error[/caption]
The workaround provided by Veeam is to create host VM-Host Affinity Rules, effectively pinning a VM to a given host, and then perform the VM backup through the host rather than through the vCenter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserve your Veeam B&amp;R Backups Jobs when Moving vCenter</title>
      <link>/virtualization/preserve-veeam-br-backups-jobs-moving-vcenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 21:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/preserve-veeam-br-backups-jobs-moving-vcenter/</guid>
      <description>This week I´m working at a client site, upgrading their entire existing vSphere 4.1 infrastructure to vSphere 5.1. The customer engagement also includes upgrading Veeam Backup and Replication 6.0 to 6.5, and usually an isolated upgrade of Veeam B&amp;amp;R is a no-brainer next, next, next, done install.
To complicate things in this particular environment, I also had to migrate the vCenter SQL DB from a local MS SQL Server 2005 Express instance to a full-fledged MS SQL Server 2008 R2 instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want a Free Pass to TechEd 2013?</title>
      <link>/news/free-pass-teched-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 16:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/news/free-pass-teched-2013/</guid>
      <description>Our sponsor Veeam is giving away a free pass to TechEd 2013 in this months giveaway.
Register now to be entered into the draw before March 18th when the winner will be announced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blatant Self Promotion</title>
      <link>/virtualization/blatant-self-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 23:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/blatant-self-promotion/</guid>
      <description>As the title says, it&amp;rsquo;s been one of my more &amp;laquo;public&amp;raquo; weeks ever. Besides my &amp;laquo;normal&amp;raquo; vSoup engagement, this week I&amp;rsquo;ve also been involved with Mike Laverick&amp;rsquo;s VMTN Subscription Movement Miniwags to voice some of my views about the #VMTNSubscriptionMovement.
Fair warning: This is video, and please to remember that during recording Movember was nearing its final phase. VMTN Subscription Movement Miniwags – Christian Mohn
Secondly, I was a guest on the Veeam Community Podcast Episode 45 – vSphere 5 Storage Potpourri.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup Academy - Do You Know Your VM backups?</title>
      <link>/virtualization/backup-academy-do-you-know-your-vm-backups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 13:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/backup-academy-do-you-know-your-vm-backups/</guid>
      <description>The newly opened Backup Academy, by Veeam, aims to educate administrators, and others interested in virtual machine backup, in the required skills to maintain a proper backup strategy for your virtual infrastructure.
Currently the site has 8 videos available, covering content from disaster recovery to backup integrity tools.
Even if it is run by Veeam, it does not focus on Veeam specific products or services, but rather on the general ideas behind a successful backup and disaster recovery of both VMware and Hyper-V based environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Expert Tips for Managing Your Remote vSphere Infrastructure</title>
      <link>/news/7-expert-tips-for-managing-your-remote-vsphere-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 20:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/news/7-expert-tips-for-managing-your-remote-vsphere-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Now there is a catchy title if I ever saw one. Only &amp;laquo;problem&amp;raquo; is that it&amp;rsquo;s a whitepaper that I have written for Veeam. In reality this is the first published article I have ever written, that I didn&amp;rsquo;t publish on my own. I&amp;rsquo;m excited about it, yet strangely nervous about how it will be received by the people who download it. If you happen to do so, make sure to let me know how you found it, all comments and criticism will be most appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using USB Pass-through in vSphere 4.1</title>
      <link>/virtualization/using-usb-pass-through-in-vsphere-4-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 23:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yourname@example.com (yourname)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/using-usb-pass-through-in-vsphere-4-1/</guid>
      <description>Finally USB pass-through is possible on ESX hosts with the new vSphere 4.1 release! This feature ha been available in VMware Workstation/Fusion and Player for quite a while. The freshly added feature in vSphere 4.1 even works if you vMotion the guest from one host to another, which is in itself pretty amazing functionality!
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to setup and use the new USB pass-through feature in vSphere 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>