<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automation on vNinja.net</title>
    <link>https://vninja.net/tags/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automation on vNinja.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Christian Mohn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 19:19:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vninja.net/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Platform Services Controller (PSC) topology and Omnigraffle</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/virtualization/vsphere-platform-services-controller-psc-topology-and-omnigraffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 19:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/virtualization/vsphere-platform-services-controller-psc-topology-and-omnigraffle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little while ago &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lamw&#34;&gt;William Lam&lt;/a&gt; published a little python script called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virtuallyghetto.com/2016/05/generating-vcenter-server-platform-services-controller-deployment-topology-diagrams.html&#34;&gt;extract_vsphere_deployment_topology.py&lt;/a&gt; that basically lets you export your current vSphere PSC topology as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DOT_(graph_description_language)&#34;&gt;DOT (graph description language)&lt;/a&gt; file. Great stuff, and in itself useful as is, especially if you run it through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webgraphviz.com&#34;&gt;webgraphviz.com&lt;/a&gt; as William suggests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, you might want to edit the topology map, change colours and fonts, and even move the boxes around, after you get the output. If you have a large environment, you might want to combine all your PSC topologies into a single document? It turns out, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to do!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining Todoist and Evernote, because awesome</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/workflow/combining-todoist-evernote-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 16:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/workflow/combining-todoist-evernote-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I declared &lt;a href=&#34;http://evernote.com&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; bankruptcy, even if I managed to misspell it while doing so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;That&amp;#39;s it, I&amp;#39;m declaring &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/evernote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@evernote&lt;/a&gt; bankrupcy.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Christian Mohn™ (@h0bbel) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/h0bbel/status/469455493631860736?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;May 22, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check for OS X Updates Automatically</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/osx/check-os-updates-automatically/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/osx/check-os-updates-automatically/</guid>
      <description>Yeah, I admit it. I want OS X Mavericks, and I want it now.
Unfortunately, it´s not available yet from Software Update. So instead of manually checking every 5 minutes or so, I decided to create a small bash script that does it for me.
It´s very, very simple, but I think it does the job:
First off, pop into Terminal and get root access:
h0bbel::h0bair { ~ }-&amp;gt; sudo su - Then create a small bash script, I named mine update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick and Dirty HTTP Based Deployment</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/virtualization/quick-and-dirty-http-based-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 11:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/virtualization/quick-and-dirty-http-based-deployment/</guid>
      <description>A lot of the scripted installation tools that VMware offers allows the usage of a central HTTP based repository for hosting the files. Today I stumbled over a little gem that might just help you create a &amp;laquo;quick and dirty&amp;raquo; HTTP based deployment scenario by running a simple command in your terminal. By default, this command works on any system that has Python installed on it, so OS X and Linux should be ready to go as is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backing up vCenter DB with Veeam B&amp;R 6.5</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/virtualization/backing-up-vcenter-db-with-veeam-br-6-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 09:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/virtualization/backing-up-vcenter-db-with-veeam-br-6-5/</guid>
      <description>It´s a well known problem that with Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Recovery Replication 6.5, and earlier, backing up the SQL server that hosts the vCenter DB poses a problem. KB1051 VSS for vCenter outlines the issue well, and provides a workaround.
If you experience this problem, you will see entries like this in your Veeam B&amp;amp;R backup logs:
 Veeam vCenterDB Backup Error
The workaround provided by Veeam is to create host VM-Host Affinity Rules, effectively pinning a VM to a given host, and then perform the VM backup through the host rather than through the vCenter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exporting vCenter Events with PowerCLI</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/virtualization/exporting-vcenter-events-powercli/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 09:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/virtualization/exporting-vcenter-events-powercli/</guid>
      <description>One of my clients has recently been having issues with their storage solution, and wanted to export the events from vCenter that show storage performance degradation, to aid in troubleshooting with the vendor.
For some reason, and I have yet to confirm that this is a bug with the vCenter 5.0 appliance or the vCenter Desktop Client, when an event export is done, the storage related events are not exported with the rest of the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applescript, Desktop Wallpaper and Growl. Automagically.</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/osx/applescript-desktop-wallpaper-growl-automatically/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 23:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/osx/applescript-desktop-wallpaper-growl-automatically/</guid>
      <description>I´ve been a Mac and OS X user now for about 7 months, but to be honest I have not been very experimental in my usage of my Macbook Air. Until now, my main focus has been basic usage of the hardware and operating systems, and making it work in my corporate environment. As I feel that I´ve reached mission accomplished status on that initial project, I decided to use some of my &amp;laquo;free&amp;raquo; vacation time to play around a bit and experiment a bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Installation and Configuring of vSphere ESXi 5</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/virtualization/auto-installation-and-configuring-of-vsphere-esxi-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 23:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/virtualization/auto-installation-and-configuring-of-vsphere-esxi-5/</guid>
      <description>One of the last projects I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with at Seatrans, is to automate the installation and configuration of vSphere ESXi 5 hosts for deployment on vessels. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked a bit about this before, both on vSoup and in Setting Up Automated ESXi Deployments where I outlined my PXE and PowerCLI based installation and configuration scheme. Not much has changed since then, except updating the PXE server to offer ESXi 5, instead of ESXi 4 and a lot of work has been put into the scripting, including a front-end GUI for the PowerCLI script itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Automated ESXi Deployments</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/virtualization/setting-up-automated-esxi-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 08:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/virtualization/setting-up-automated-esxi-deployments/</guid>
      <description>Automating ESXi installs was made much easier after the release of vSphere 4.1 where the Scripted Install feature was added, and by using VMware Auto Deploy from VMware Labs. VMware Auto Deploy requires that you have vCenter and Host Profiles in your environment, and that again requires that you have Enterprise Plus licenses in your environment.
It is, however, possible to deploy ESXi in an automated fashion completely without vCenter and Host Profiles!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>