<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Beautiful Hugo</title>
    <link>/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Beautiful Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 12:33:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS: Vanilla</title>
      <link>/osx/macos-vanilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 12:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/osx/macos-vanilla/</guid>
      <description>Small, unobtrusive and easy to use. That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good description for a macOS utility I recently discovered: Vanilla (non-affiliate link).
Simply put, this little gem let&amp;rsquo;s you hide any or all menu bar icons in macOS, while still keeping them easily accessible behind a small arrow:
After hiding with Vanilla:
Expanded view:I for one like getting rid of the unnecessary clutter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Royal TSX Even More Awesome</title>
      <link>/osx/making-royal-tsx-even-more-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 21:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/osx/making-royal-tsx-even-more-awesome/</guid>
      <description>For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, Royal TSX is an awesome Remote Management solution, which supports RDP, VNC, SSH, S/FTP and even ESXi and vCenter. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for years, not just because they offer free licenses for vExperts (and others), but simply because it works really well. Store it&amp;rsquo;s config file on a synchronized file area (like Dropbox), and boom, your config follows you around from machine to machine, including custom icons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS: Spectacle</title>
      <link>/osx/macos-spectacle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 09:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/osx/macos-spectacle/</guid>
      <description>Working with the keyboard to move resize, focus and arrange your applications is a great productivity tip. When I changed from Windows to macOS a few years ago, I had a pretty convoluted setup based on Slate for managing keyboard shortcuts, especially for moving applications around, but this has since been simplified by using Spectacle instead of Slate.
Spectacle has everything I need, especially keyboard shortcuts for maximising an application, of &amp;ldquo;flinging&amp;rdquo; it over to another display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS: Secure Pipes</title>
      <link>/osx/macos-secure-pipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 13:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/osx/macos-secure-pipes/</guid>
      <description>Since I set up a public jumphost for my homelab/network, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for an easy way to manage my SSH tunnels. After trying a couple of different managers, I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to use Secure Pipes.This little piece of free software allows you to easily manage SSH tunnels, with features like Remote Forwards, Local Forwards and SOCKS proxies. It runs in the toolbar, and makes connections easily available. It even reconfigures your network settings to use the SOCKS proxy, if allowed to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>