<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on Adventures in Hugo</title>
    <link>/categories/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on Adventures in Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Christian Mohn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 13:18:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Patch those Dell Servers easily!</title>
      <link>/posts/patch-those-dell-servers-easily/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 13:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/patch-those-dell-servers-easily/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that Dell has a bootable linux ISO with firmware upgrades for their servers available? Neither did I, but luckily I found it today when needing it at a customer site.
Check out Updating Dell PowerEdge servers via bootable media / ISO where you can download bootable ISOs for specific server models, and get all your firmware upgraded in one fell swoop.
Be warned though, it takes quite some time to run though it all (125 update packages in this instance), but it sure beats installing manually or creating your own bootable ISO with the Dell Repository Manager or even using Dell Server Update Utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HP ProLiant MicroServer – Oh, it&#39;s there!</title>
      <link>/posts/hp-proliant-microserver-%e2%80%93-oh-its-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 08:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hp-proliant-microserver-%e2%80%93-oh-its-there/</guid>
      <description>In a previous article, HP ProLiant MicroServer – Not Quite There Yet?, I questioned whether the HP Proliant MicroServer could have a place in a corporate environment.
I finally got my hands on one, and for my specific use case it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much perfect! Sure, I would love to have some vSphere supported RAID controller and a beefier CPU but in my use case the MicroServer delivers just what we need for some of our small branch offices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HP ProLiant MicroServer - Not Quite There Yet?</title>
      <link>/posts/hp-proliant-microserver-not-quite-there-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 22:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hp-proliant-microserver-not-quite-there-yet/</guid>
      <description>When HP announced their new ProLiant MicroServer, I really hoped that it would be the perfect answer to a specific use case I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at lately.
Basically, what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for is a small chassis, low noise branch office server that would be used to host a single virtual machine, offering Read-Only Domain Controller (RODC) and Distributed File System (DFS) file-shares.
Initially it looked to fit the bill perfectly:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>