<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Labs on Adventures in Hugo</title>
    <link>/tags/labs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Labs on Adventures in Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Christian Mohn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 08:50:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brilliant idea: VMware Hosted Beta</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/brilliant-idea-vmware-hosted-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 08:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/vmware-2/brilliant-idea-vmware-hosted-beta/</guid>
      <description>Duncan Epping rather unceremoniously published a blog post &amp;ldquo;New Beta Program offering: VMware Hosted Beta&amp;rdquo; yesterday, outlining the availability of the new hosted beta offering that companions some of the current VMware beta programs.
_Due to the very NDA nature of the beta programs, I can´t really go into details on what is currently offered, but what I can say is this: Well done VMware!_
The VMware Hosted Beta runs on the same engine that runs the VMware Hands on Labs Online – Beta, but with a little added twist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupported Network Configurations in Virtual Appliances</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/unsupported-network-configurations-virtual-appliances/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 23:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/vmware-2/unsupported-network-configurations-virtual-appliances/</guid>
      <description>My recent experience with setting up vCenter Operations Manager on a standalone ESXi host, and the always excellent William Lam´s post Automating VCSA Network Configurations For Greenfield Deployments got me thinking.
There are several other appliances out there that require deployment to a vCenter, to be able to configure the networking options and not just default to DHCP. In many, and perhaps even most, cases you can work around that by running the _vami_set_network _command to change from DHCP to STATIC network configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting It Right: VMware Training and Certification</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/right-vmware-training-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 21:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/vmware-2/right-vmware-training-certification/</guid>
      <description>Everyone, and probably their extended family including their mother-in-law, has heard me whine and complain about the VCP training requirements.
VMware has unveiled a new lab, namely Project Nee (Next-Generation Education Environment)
and this is something I´m really excited about.
Project Nee is described as this:
VMware Project NEE is a new VMware Labs project providing a richly featured, powerful online learning and lab environment delivered from the cloud to any device, anywhere, anytime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Virtual Customer Labs</title>
      <link>/news/vmware-virtual-customer-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 18:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/vmware-virtual-customer-labs/</guid>
      <description>I´ve mentioned this earlier, VMware hands-in labs going public in 2012, but finally it seems like something is happening in that regard!
Scott Sauer has announced the availability of &amp;ldquo;VMware Virtual Customer Labs” (vCL) where he walks us through the setup and delivery of the new vCL offering.
At the moment it´s only available to &amp;ldquo;selected customers&amp;rdquo;, supported by a VMware pre-sales engineer, and the number of labs are limited. It´s still a work in progress, and I´m sure great things will come out of this!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Hands-on Labs going public in 2012</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vmworld-hands-on-labs-going-public-in-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 10:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/virtualization/vmworld-hands-on-labs-going-public-in-2012/</guid>
      <description>VMware Labs now has fixed data centers which means that the VMworld Hands-On labs are going to be publicly available in early 20112!
Hear Mornay Van Der Walt, Senior Director R&amp;amp;D at VMware, explain the details in this video from VMworld TV:
This is great news, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who thinks this is a really good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>