<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simulation on Adventures in Hugo</title>
    <link>/tags/simulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simulation on Adventures in Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Christian Mohn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 14:21:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and Configuring WANem Virtual Appliance</title>
      <link>/posts/installing-and-configuring-wanem-virtual-appliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 14:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/installing-and-configuring-wanem-virtual-appliance/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, Using the WANem WAN Emulator Virtual Appliance, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about how I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully used WANem to emulate different WAN scenarios.
Since I work for a shipping company, the ability to emulate VSAT conditions are especially useful for testing and proof-of-concept scenarios.
You can use WANem a couple of different ways but my setup is pretty simple but does the job perfectly.
Downloading WANem I have chose to use the WANem Virtual Appliance running in a virtual machine hosted by VMware Workstation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the WANem WAN Emulator Virtual Appliance</title>
      <link>/posts/using-the-wanem-wan-emulator-virtual-appliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 11:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/using-the-wanem-wan-emulator-virtual-appliance/</guid>
      <description>During preparation and preliminary information gathering for a new internal project, I had a need to emulate various networking conditions and scenarios. More specifically I&amp;rsquo;m looking at the possibility of running the vCenter Client over high latency satellite links, with varying bandwidth availability and even packet loss scenarios.
Obviously the best way of testing this, in a controlled environment, is to use some kind of WAN emulator that lets you control the various networking characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>