<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft on Adventures in Hugo</title>
    <link>/categories/microsoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft on Adventures in Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Christian Mohn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 16:01:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Relax and virtualize it!</title>
      <link>/virtualization/relax-and-virtualize-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 16:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/virtualization/relax-and-virtualize-it/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post from Kristian Wæraas Senior Consultant Datacenter at Datametrix AS VMware VCP3/5, MCTS Hyper-V, Horizon View and Trend Micro Security Expert.
I am a curious by nature, and when my colleagues start talking frantic about some system that has crashed, I get curious and have to ask questions. Usually this ends up in me doing a lot of work.
- This, however, was not one of those times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Microsoft really be Fair and Balanced?</title>
      <link>/virtualization/microsoft-fair-balanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 23:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/virtualization/microsoft-fair-balanced/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has launched Virtualization2, a program to educate VMware administrators on Hyper-V and the System Center suite of tools. In short, these arefree online training sessiosn on November 19th and 20th, that also comes with a voucher for their new Microsoft virtualization certification exam (74-409).
This comes in addition to their existing Microsoft Virtualization for VMware Professionals Jump Start training course.
I think this is a good idea, and if you are able to close your eyes to the hyperbole, and disregard things like &amp;ldquo;Microsoft Wants to Help VMware Experts “Future-Proof “ Their Career&amp;rdquo;, I applaud this initiative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and Using a Virtual Floppy in vSphere</title>
      <link>/virtualization/creating-virtual-floppy-vsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 22:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/virtualization/creating-virtual-floppy-vsphere/</guid>
      <description>My new colleague Olav Tvedt asked me if I could test his method of enabling Bitlocker in a VM, on VMware vSphere. Of course, I was happy to oblige.
I followed the same steps as he did in his Running Bitlocker on a Virtual computer post, and it worked perfectly.
The only real difference between doing this in Hyper-V and on ESXi, is that the virtual floppy drive on ESXi by default doesn&amp;rsquo;t emulate an empty floppy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCCM 2007 Not a Virtualization Candidate?</title>
      <link>/microsoft-2/sccm-2007-not-a-virtualization-candidate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 08:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microsoft-2/sccm-2007-not-a-virtualization-candidate/</guid>
      <description>The last couple of days I&amp;rsquo;ve been in training class, taking the 6451B Planning, Deploying and Managing Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager 2007 course.
One of the first things that got mentioned, was that for larger deployments you should not run System Center Configuration Manager virtually. Of course, this caught my eye as I&amp;rsquo;m a proponent for the virtualize first &amp;ldquo;movement&amp;rdquo;.
It runs out that the reason for this is that Configuration Manager is somewhat poorly designed, as just about everything it receives from the clients in the network is placed in text based log files (inbox folder) before being processed and pumped into the back-end SQL DB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s WSUS</title>
      <link>/microsoft-2/poor-mans-wsus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 21:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microsoft-2/poor-mans-wsus/</guid>
      <description>Not that WSUS is expensive, after all it&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; addon to the server you&amp;rsquo;re already running if you need it. Of course, running your own Windows Server Update Services (WSUS) infrastructure is preferable in just about every scenario except for some edge cases where bandwidth or latency issues might prevent you from syncing the updates from a central repository. Sadly, these edge cases enter the fray from time to time and I recently found myself in the middle of such a scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange 2010 SP1 and KB2393802 or How to Have an Interesting Afternoon at the Office</title>
      <link>/microsoft-2/exchange-2010-sp1-and-kb2393802-or-how-to-have-an-interesting-afternoon-at-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 12:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microsoft-2/exchange-2010-sp1-and-kb2393802-or-how-to-have-an-interesting-afternoon-at-the-office/</guid>
      <description>Let me start this post out with a little story. I am normally a hardcore virtualization and storage guy. Sometimes my career in this sector brings me into working with stuff I haven&amp;rsquo;t worked with before because virtualization encompasses so much. As I continue to work with other teams I learn more and more about what they do everyday. I usually find myself involved in every performance troubleshooting session and every new project these days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>