<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Free Tools on Adventures in Hugo</title>
    <link>/tags/free-tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Free Tools on Adventures in Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Christian Mohn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 11:45:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/free-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinapped vSphere Client Updated to V5.0</title>
      <link>/vmware-2/thinapped-vsphere-client-updated-v5-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 11:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/vmware-2/thinapped-vsphere-client-updated-v5-0/</guid>
      <description>The Thinapped vSphere Client has finally been updated to v5.0, and is readily available for download!
Sadly the new version is v5.0 only, and will only allow you to connect to vSphere v5 hosts and since the new release has replaced the old release on the VMware Fling website, you´re out of luck if you haven´t already got the 4.0 version stowed away in your own private locker.
I hope VMware decides to either make the 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and Configuring WANem Virtual Appliance</title>
      <link>/virtualization/installing-and-configuring-wanem-virtual-appliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 14:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/virtualization/installing-and-configuring-wanem-virtual-appliance/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, Using the WANem WAN Emulator Virtual Appliance, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about how I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully used WANem to emulate different WAN scenarios.
Since I work for a shipping company, the ability to emulate VSAT conditions are especially useful for testing and proof-of-concept scenarios.
You can use WANem a couple of different ways but my setup is pretty simple but does the job perfectly.
Downloading WANem I have chose to use the WANem Virtual Appliance running in a virtual machine hosted by VMware Workstation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the WANem WAN Emulator Virtual Appliance</title>
      <link>/network/using-the-wanem-wan-emulator-virtual-appliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 11:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/network/using-the-wanem-wan-emulator-virtual-appliance/</guid>
      <description>During preparation and preliminary information gathering for a new internal project, I had a need to emulate various networking conditions and scenarios. More specifically I&amp;rsquo;m looking at the possibility of running the vCenter Client over high latency satellite links, with varying bandwidth availability and even packet loss scenarios.
Obviously the best way of testing this, in a controlled environment, is to use some kind of WAN emulator that lets you control the various networking characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds VM Console</title>
      <link>/virtualization/solarwinds-vm-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 13:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/virtualization/solarwinds-vm-console/</guid>
      <description>SolarWinds has released a new free vSphere tool called SolarWinds VM Console.
Free VM Console Highlights:
 Bounce (shutdown &amp;amp; restart) VMs without logging into vCenter or vSphere
 Get end-to-end visibility into your VMware environment—from vCenter through ESX hosts to VM guests
 Track the real-time up/down status of your VMs from your desktop — without logging into VMware apps
  Additional VM Monitoring Features:
 Take a snapshot of your VM prior to shutdown</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>