<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workstation 8 on Beautiful Hugo</title>
    <link>/tags/workstation-8/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workstation 8 on Beautiful Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 09:18:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/workstation-8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Simulation in VMware Workstation 8</title>
      <link>/virtualization/network-simulation-in-vmware-workstation-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 09:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/network-simulation-in-vmware-workstation-8/</guid>
      <description>In the new VMware Workstation 8 release, VMware has added a rudimentary network simulation setting where you can tweak bandwidth and packet loss for a given network card. Very useful when testing applications and servers and want to know how they react to network issues, or if you want to simulate a WAN link. I know this was available in Workstation 7 as well, but it used to be a team feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Windows 8 Developer Preview in VMware Workstation 8</title>
      <link>/virtualization/installing-windows-8-developer-preview-in-vmware-workstation-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 12:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/installing-windows-8-developer-preview-in-vmware-workstation-8/</guid>
      <description>Installing Microsoft Windows 8 in a VMware Workstation 8 VM turned out to be a real piece of cake.
Follow the screenshots for the procedure I used, but basically all I did was to create a new VM with the pre-configured &amp;ldquo;Windows 8 Server&amp;rdquo; preset and inserted the downloaded ISO file.
Note: Windows 8 Server has been removed as a preset option in the final release of VMware Workstation 8, my screenshots are from the beta version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Workstation 8 - What&#39;s new?</title>
      <link>/virtualization/vmware-workstation-8-whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 12:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/virtualization/vmware-workstation-8-whats-new/</guid>
      <description>VMware is close (still in beta) to releasing the new major release of VMware Workstation.
Update 14. September 2011: VMware Workstation 8 has now officially been released.
VMware Workstation 8 brings a lot of new features and enhancements to the table, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough to play around with it in the beta program.
VMware Workstation 8 System Requirements To be able to install VMware Workstation, the host system processor needs to meet the following requirements:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>