<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patching on Beautiful Hugo</title>
    <link>/tags/patching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Patching on Beautiful Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 13:18:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/patching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Patch those Dell Servers easily!</title>
      <link>/hardware/patch-those-dell-servers-easily/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 13:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/hardware/patch-those-dell-servers-easily/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that Dell has a bootable linux ISO with firmware upgrades for their servers available? Neither did I, but luckily I found it today when needing it at a customer site.
Check out Updating Dell PowerEdge servers via bootable media / ISO where you can download bootable ISOs for specific server models, and get all your firmware upgraded in one fell swoop.
Be warned though, it takes quite some time to run though it all (125 update packages in this instance), but it sure beats installing manually or creating your own bootable ISO with the Dell Repository Manager or even using Dell Server Update Utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s WSUS</title>
      <link>/microsoft-2/poor-mans-wsus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 21:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Some Person)</author>
      <guid>/microsoft-2/poor-mans-wsus/</guid>
      <description>Not that WSUS is expensive, after all it&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; addon to the server you&amp;rsquo;re already running if you need it. Of course, running your own Windows Server Update Services (WSUS) infrastructure is preferable in just about every scenario except for some edge cases where bandwidth or latency issues might prevent you from syncing the updates from a central repository. Sadly, these edge cases enter the fray from time to time and I recently found myself in the middle of such a scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>