<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homelab on vNinja.net</title>
    <link>https://vninja.net/tags/homelab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homelab on vNinja.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Christian Mohn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 11:31:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vninja.net/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging SSH logins to Slack</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/homelab/logging-ssh-logins-to-slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 11:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/homelab/logging-ssh-logins-to-slack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href=&#34;http://vninja.net/homelab/homelabops-via-slack/&#34;&gt;Slack to alert and log &lt;/a&gt;a few things in my environment, and one of the things I use it for is to alert me if someone logs on via SSH to my public facing Jumphost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For a good walkthrough on how to set up such a host, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virtualtothecore.com/en/tunnel-all-your-remote-connections-through-ssh-with-a-linux-jumpbox/&#34;&gt;Tunnel all your remote connections through ssh with a linux jumpbox&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dellock6&#34;&gt;Luca Dell&amp;rsquo;Oca&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudFlare Dynamic DNS Update Script (cf-ddns.sh)</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/homelab/cloudflare-dynamic-dns-update-script-cf-ddns-sh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 09:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/homelab/cloudflare-dynamic-dns-update-script-cf-ddns-sh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a part of my&lt;a href=&#34;http://vninja.net/homelab/&#34;&gt; Homelab&lt;/a&gt; project, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a proper bash script to provide dynamic DNS updates for external resources, via CloudFlare. More details on the reasoning behind it can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;http://vninja.net/homelab/using-cloudflare-for-dynamic-dns/&#34;&gt;Using CloudFlare for Dynamic DNS&lt;/a&gt;, but since that was posted I&amp;rsquo;ve fleshed the script out quite a bit more.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CloudFlare for Dynamic DNS</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/homelab/using-cloudflare-for-dynamic-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 22:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/homelab/using-cloudflare-for-dynamic-dns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vninja.net/homelab/dynamic-dns-requirements/&#34;&gt;In my previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I tried to lay out the foundation and reasoning behind requiring a Dynamic DNS Service, and here is how I solved it using CloudFlare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, I moved my chosen domain name to CloudFlare, and made sure everything resolved ok with static records. Once that was working, I started playing around with the CloudFlare API, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://mmattozzi.github.io/cocoa-rest-client/&#34;&gt;Cocoa Rest Client&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m no developer (as is probably very apparent by the script below), nor API wizard of any kind, but it was fairly easy figuring out how to craft a request that lists my DNS zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic DNS Requirements</title>
      <link>https://vninja.net/homelab/dynamic-dns-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 22:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vninja.net/homelab/dynamic-dns-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While working on my new &lt;a href=&#34;http://vninja.net/news/taking-it-to-far/&#34;&gt;Homelab&lt;/a&gt; setup, I&amp;rsquo;ve been investigating ways to provide hostname based access to several web services located in my DMZ zone. Since my provider doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide static IP addresses, I also need an external Dynamic DNS service, to provide said hostname mappings through the reverse proxy on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are loads of Dynamic DNS services available, most of them lets you use some sort of predefined domain name scheme, and point it to your external IP, but I wanted to use a domain name that I own and control. Since I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudflare.com&#34;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt; to provide DNS services (amongst other things) for this very site, it was a natural choice to see if they could fit the bill for my lab needs as well. Turns out, not only can they provide the services I need for free, they also allow me to play around and have fun at the same time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>